Teach
us,
Kunundo
Teach
us,
Kunundo
Teach
n
do
us,
Teach
Ku
nu
Teach
Ku
nu
Teach
Ku
nu
いきなり
Surprise!
n
do
教えて　くぬどーん
Teach us, Kunudon!
we provide the ideal environment for drawing out burgeoning potential.
By upholding our principles of high-growth education,
やあ　みんな　くぬどんだよ
we provide the ideal environment for drawing out burgeoning potential.
By upholding our principles of high-growth education,
Hi, everybody! It's me, Kunudon!
we provide the ideal environment for drawing out burgeoning potential.
くぬどんさまー
Kunudon-sama!
椚ヶ丘学園の成績優秀者たちには　素晴らしい権利が贈られるんだ
The students with the best grades at Kunugigaoka Academy are entitled to a fantastic privilege:
既得権益
Vested interest!
常夏の沖縄で過ごす　ぜいたくな夏期講習２泊３日
Three days and two nights at a luxury summer school in always-summery Okinawa!
公用旅券
Official passports!
Boost Your Concentration in the Open Air!
The school pays for the hotel and everything that goes with it.
ホテルと提携しているサービスは全て学校が負担
Boost Your Concentration in the Open Air!
思う存分に自主勉強に励めます
Students can study to their hearts' content!
酒池肉林
Sheer debauchery! Yay!
What? What do you mean, the E Class is going?!
なっ　Ｅ組の連中が行く…だと
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on!
起立
礼
ロックオン
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on!
起立
礼
ロックオン
oh yeah
Oh yeah!
sensei target on
The target is our teacher!
せんせー
ターゲットオン
ポテンシャル高い
potential takai
We've got a lot of potential
hodo mendokusai
It's just that we're not trying
ほどめんどくさい
dropout mentality
We had that dropouts' mentality
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
hinichijou wo ryougashi
No matter the unusual situation we were in
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
非日常を凌駕し
僕らはうたたね顔して
bokura wa utatatanegao shite
We pretended to doze off
knife kakushimotta
While holding on to a hidden knife
翻译...兰樱
校对...Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
起立
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on
礼
ロックオン
hottokeba kitto dareka yatte kureru to
Thinking someone would deal with you eventually
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...歪歪
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...歪歪
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...歪歪
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
doko ka taningoto datta
We didn't really feel invested in the job
どこか　他人事だった
だけど
dakedo
But now
だけど
mister teacher oshiete mikansei na bokura
Teacher, teach us, we're still growing up
Mr.ティーチャー教えて　未完成の僕ら
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
anata to iu furaku no target uchinukeru deshou ka
Will we be able to shoot through an invincible target like you?
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
idomu tabi ni kanousei ga afureta
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
Our chances soar each time we challenge you
Stand, bow, lock on! Stand, bow, lock on!
idomu tabi ni kanousei ga afureta
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
挑む限り
可能性はハーフ＆ハーフ
mister teacher mite ite mayoi ooki bokura
Teacher, watch us, as we try to find a direction in life
Mr.ティーチャー見ていて　迷い多き僕ら
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
dare yori mo anata no tame ni moubenkyouchuu sa
We're studying our ass off for you more than anybody else
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
殺意だけが
satsui dake ga anata e no message
Only the bloodlust is our message to you
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on! Stand, bow, lock on!
殺意だけが
あなたへのメッセージ
jiriki gachi de hongan iku yo
We'll make our dreams come true on our own for real
あなたへのメッセージ
自力　ガチで
本願　行くよ
revolution
A revolution!
レボリューション
oh yeah
Oh yeah!
レボリューション
sensei target on
The target is our teacher!
せんせー
ターゲットオン
Episode
Island
Time
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 及微博 @诸神字幕组
Whoa, just look at 'em all!
おい　見ろよ　うじゃうじゃいるぜ
Summer vacation had begun...
夏休みも始まり　学校から解き放たれてフリーダム
and with it came our freedom!
Or so you'd think.
…と思いきや
Why are we here at school?
何で　僕ら　学校に来てんのかな…
Well... I don't want people to see me out catching bugs at my age.
いや～　いい年してみんなの前で昆虫採集とか　恥ずかしいだろ
But I've always wanted to do this, and I never got a chance in the city.
俺　街育ちだからさ　こういうの憧れてたんだ
偶然　業が虫がいる木見つけたって言っててさ
Plus, Karma happened to point me to a tree with some good bugs on it.
Though I didn't expect you to come, Maehara.
しかし　前原まで来るとは意外だわ
Never pegged you as an insect fan.
こんな遊び興味ないと思ってた
Our next assassination's at that island resort, right?
次の暗殺は南国リゾート島でやるわけじゃん
Wouldn't you say we're missing a little something?
そしたら　何か足りないと思わねえか
Like what?
何が
Money!
金さ
You need buying power if you're gonna snag yourself a swimsuited babe!
水着で泳ぐ奇麗なちゃんねーを落とすためには財力が不可欠
That runt won't do the trick,
こんな雑魚じゃ　駄目だろうけど
but a giant stag beetle?
オオクワガタ　あれとか　ウン万円するらしいじゃん
Those babies'll net you tens of thousands of yen!
ネトオクに出して大もうけ
Auction 'em off online for major cashola,
最低でも　高級ディナー代とご休憩場所の予算までは確保するんだー
and we'll make at least enough to cover a fancy dinner and a place to chill out!
I think he's forgotten what this trip's all about.
旅の目的忘れてねえか　前原のやつ
Yeah. That wasn't your average
fifteen-year-old's vacation plans.
うん　１５歳の旅行プランとは思えないよね
That won't work!
駄目　駄目
オオクワはもう古いよ
Giant stag beetles're old and busted.
倉橋
Kurahashi!
Morning! You're here to scrape up some spending money too, huh?
おっはー　みんなもお小遣い稼ぎに来たんだね
Hey, what do you mean, stag beetles are old and busted?
倉橋　オオクワガタが古いとか　どういうことだ
Well...
んっとね
I guess they were super valuable right around when we were born,
私たちが生まれたころは　すごい値段だったらしいけどね
but today's artificial breeding methods have saturated the market,
今は人工繁殖法が確立されちゃって
大量に出回り過ぎて　値崩れしたんだってさ
bringing their prices way down.
You mean the beetle bubble burst?!
ま…まさかのクワ大暴落か
１クワ１ちゃんねーぐらいの相場と思ってたのに…
I figured one beetle would make around enough to cover one babe...
ないない　今はちゃんねーの方が高いと思うよ
No way. These days, babes are way more expensive.
You sure know a lot about this, Kurahashi. Are you into bugs?
詳しいな　倉橋
好きなのか　昆虫
Yep! Along with every other living thing!
うん　生き物は全部好き
Hey, since we're all here...
ねえねえ　せっかくだし　みんなで捕まえよう
Let's all go bug-hunting!
We're bound to find tons if we all try!
多人数で数揃えるのが確実だよ
The innocent and genuine Kurahashi-san
天真らんまんな倉橋さんは生物の話題にめっぽう強い
knows an insane amount about living creatures.
Just the right helping hand for a bunch of crass-ish guys to have around.
ゲス方向に傾いていた男子パーティーには心強い助っ人だ
Mmm. Pretty nice haul.
そこそこ引っ掛かったね
Whoa! Did you set this?
これ　お前が仕掛けておいたのか
It's a home-made trap of mine.
お手製のトラップだよ
I put it out last night.
昨日の夜につけといたんだ
Let ferment for 1-2 days
There are about twenty more of them out there,
あと２０カ所ぐらい仕掛けたから
so that's about a thousand yen for each of us if we're lucky!
うまくすれば　一人１０００円くらい稼げるよ
Not too shabby for a side job!
バイトとしちゃ　まずまずか
探してたあれ　来てるといいな
I hope we caught the one I was looking for!
効率の悪いトラップだ
What an inefficient trap.
And you call yourselves the E Class?
それでもお前らＥ組か
Okajima!
岡島
Pulling in a measly thousand yen at a time? Yeah, right.
せこせこ　１０００円稼いでる場合かよ
My trap'll bring in a cool ten billion!
俺のトラップで狙うのは　当然１００億だ
Ten billion... You don't mean—
１００億って…
Oh, but I do.
そのとおり
南の島で暗殺するって予定だから
If we're planning an assassination on this tropical isle,
that octopus is bound to let his guard down in the meantime.
あのタコもそれまでは油断するはず
And that's what I'm after!
そこが俺の狙い目だ
Stag
All right! Here we go!
掛かってる　掛かってる
He went right for my porno trap!
俺の仕掛けたエロ本トラップに
Wow. When do you see the speedy Korosensei too absorbed in reading to make the slightest movement?
すげえ…
スピード自慢の殺せんせーが　微動だにせず見入っている
That one must be right up his alley.
よほど好みのエロ本なのか
And what's with the stag beetle getup?
また何だ　あのカブトムシのコスプレは
あれで擬態してるつもりか　嘆かわしい
Is he trying to blend in? That's just sad.
Every mountain has one: the smut stash.
どの山にも存在するんだ　エロ本　廃棄スポットがな
そこで　夢を拾った子供が
The kids who find their dreams there grow old enough to buy their own porn mags
大人になって本を買えるよわいになり
and then leave behind dreams for someone else to find.
今度はそこに夢を置いていく
Please dispose of recyclables responsibly as per your local council's arrangements.
It's a place filled with neverending dreams.
終わらない夢を見る場所なんだ
I'm glad you're here! Lend me a hand!
ちょうどいい　手伝えよ
俺たちのエロの力で　覚めない夢を見せてやろうぜ
We'll use our porn power to give him a dream he'll never wake up from!
We seem to have reached maximum crassitude.
パーティーが致命的にゲスくなった
I did some major research into his top turn-ons, y'know.
ずいぶん研究したんだぜ　あいつの好みを
Can't buy the stuff myself, but I found a few.
俺だって買えないから　拾い集めてな
Wouldn't he like anything with big boobs?
殺せんせー　巨乳なら何でもいいんじゃ…
現実ではそうだけどな
In real life, sure.
A hit
But dirty magazines are dreams.
エロ本は夢だ
Everyone looks for their ideal in those pages.
A miss.
人は誰もそこに自分の理想を求める
For photos and manga alike, the tiniest
difference gets a whole 'nother response.
Photos a hit,
setup doesn't sit well
写真も漫画も　わずかな差で反応が全然違うんだ
That's amazing, Okajima-kun. So for the last month,
すごいよ　岡島君
１カ月間　本を入れ替えてつぶさに反応を観察してる
you've been placing different kinds of porn and carefully observing his reactions?
What kind of grown-up would spend a whole month picking up abandoned porn mags?
ていうか　大の大人が１カ月連続で拾い読むなよ　嘆かわしい
That's just sad.
It's just like your traps, Kurahashi.
お前のトラップと同じだよ　倉橋
You need to work out ways to attract your prey for long periods of time, right?
獲物が長時間夢中になるよう　研究するだろ
Yeah.
うん
I've got a dirty mind.
俺はエロいさ　さげすむやつはそれでも結構
If you wanna hate me for it, go on ahead.
But it's only because I'm a super-lech that I know:
だがな　誰よりエロい俺だから知っている
Pornography can save the world.
エロは世界を救えるって
How did he make that sound so cool?!
な…何か　カッコイイ
I'll get him, all right!
やるぜ
Under all that porn is a net strung with anti-teacher BB pellets!
エロ本の下に対先生弾をつなぎ合わせたネットを仕込んだ
He's buried in that mag right now. We can nab him for sure!
熱中してる今なら　必ず掛かる
Someone cut this rope and trigger the trap.
誰かこのロープを切って発動させろ
I'll jump in there and finish him off!
俺が飛び出してとどめを刺す
Anything can be a sword if you polish it enough.
どんなものでも　研ぎ澄ませばやいばになる
Okajima-kun's porn-sword might just run Korosensei through.
岡島君のエロのやいばが殺せんせーを貫くかもしれない
Bwoop!
Wh-What the...
な…何だ
His eyes just went all "bwoop"!
急に目がみよ～んって…
I don't have any data on that face!
データにないぞ　あの顔は
What kind of porn does that signify?!
どんなエロを見たときだ
Stag
There you are!
見つけましたよ
Stag
A Miyama stag beetle.
ミヤマクワガタ　しかもこの目の色
And look at that eye color!
Are they white, Korosensei?
白なの　殺せんせー
おや　倉橋さん
Ah, Kurahashi-san!
Indeed they are!
ビンゴですよ
すっごい　探してたやつだ
Wow! Just what I've been looking for!
Yes, right here on this mountain!
ええ　この山にもいたんですね
Oh, man! And we were so close!
あとちょっとだったのに
Miyama stag! Miyama stag! Yay!
I don't know what they're so happy about,
何で喜んでんのかさっぱりだが
but a giant stag beetle and a junior-high girl jumping around on all that porn?
巨大カブトと女子中学生がエロ本の上で跳びはねてんのはすごい光景だ…
That's one hell of a sight.
Mortifying! How super-duper mortifying!
超恥ずかしい…　超　超　超恥ずかしい…
I'm so ashamed. Such behavior is unbecoming of an educator.
面目ない　教育者としてあるまじき姿を
I knew there was a trap under all this porn,
本の下にわながあるのは知ってましたが
but with each magazine more to my taste than the last,
どんどん先生好みになる本の誘惑に耐え切れず
I couldn't resist!
すんなりバレてた…
He saw right through it...
So what's the big deal, Kurahashi?
で　どういうことよ　倉橋
それって　ミヤマクワガタだろ
That's a Miyama stag beetle, right?
In games and stuff, they sell for way less than a giant stag.
ゲームとかじゃ　オオクワガタより全然安いぜ
最近は　ミヤマの方が高いときが多いんだよ
Miyamas've been selling for more lately.
まだ繁殖が難しいから
They're still hard to breed.
このサイズなら　２万はいくかも
One this size could fetch twenty thousand.
２万
Twenty thousand?!
Plus, take a good look at his eyes.
おまけに　よーく目を見てください
They're usually black, but these are white.
本来黒いはずの目が白いでしょう
I taught you about albinism in biology class, right?
生物でアルビノ個体については教えましたね
Oh, yeah... Like the super-rare creatures born pure white?
ああ　ごくたまに全身真っ白で生まれてくるやつだろ
Yes, and albino stag beetles are only white in the eyes.
はい　クワガタのアルビノは目だけに出ます
A natural-born Miyama white-eye, as they're known, is extremely rare.
ホワイトアイと呼ばれ
天然ミヤマのホワイトアイはとんでもなく希少です
Why, this even has academic value.
学術的な価値すらある
You could sell this for hundreds of thousands of yen, easy.
売れば　おそらく数十万円はくだらない
すっ
Hundreds?!
I told Korosensei I was hoping I could see one someday,
一度は見てみたいって　殺せんせーに話したらさ
ズーム目で探してくれるって　言ってたんだ
and he said he'd use his zoom eyes to find one for me!
Okay, you lowlifes: whoever wants this baby, raise your hand!
ゲスなみんな　これ欲しい人　手挙げて
Me!
欲しい
どうしよっかな
What to do, what to do?
I was the one who caught it!
捕まえたのは先生なんですから
In killing, in porn, in living things:
殺しにエロに生き物に　夏休みの学校も発見がいっぱい
summer vacation is full of learning and discoveries.
One more week until our assassination vacation to that tropical island.
南の島の暗殺旅行まで　あと１週間
Old Campus
One more week until our assassination vacation to that tropical island.
南の島　暗殺旅行まで　あと１週間
Old Campus
We'd gotten together to train for it and put our plans in order.
僕たちはその訓練と計画の詰めのために集まっていた
Well, well! I see you little brats are working up a good sweat,
まあまあ　がきども
夏休みだというのに　汗水流して　ご苦労なことね
summer vacation notwithstanding.
You should train too, Bitch-sensei.
ビッチ先生も訓練しろよ
射撃やナイフは俺らと大差ないだろうにさ
Your gun and knife skills aren't that much better than ours.
Grownups are sneaky.
大人はずるいのよ
I'll just hitch a ride on your strategy and take the best parts for myself.
あんたたちの作戦に乗じて　おいしいとこだけ持ってくわ
You think you're a big shot, huh, Irina?
偉いもんだな　イリーナ
ロッ　ロヴロ先生
L-Lovro-sensei!
He's here as a special instructor for the summer.
夏休みの特別講師で来てもらった
He'll give us tips on our strategy from a pro's perspective.
みんなが考えた作戦に　プロの視点から助言をくれる
１日休めば　指や腕は殺しを忘れる
Spend one day resting, and your fingers and arms forget about killing.
If you don't want to flunk out, hurry and get changed!
落第が嫌なら　さっさと着替えろ
ヘ…ヘイ　喜んで
Yes, sir!
Even Bitch-sensei can't say no to him.
ビッチ先生も　あの師匠には頭上がらねえな
Yeah, well, he's one scary dude.
ああ　てか　あの人いかにも怖いもん
Thank you for your assistance.
協力　感謝する
To make matters worse,
困ったことが重なってな
I lost contact with the assassins who'd shown the most promise.
有望だった殺し屋たちと連絡がつかなくなった
プロたちが失敗していることを知っておじけづいた
Were they scared off, knowing that even the pros had failed?
Perhaps.
かもしれんな
Now all we can do is leave it up to them.
今は彼らに託すしかあるまい
それで　今日やつはここにはいないんだな
In any case, am I correct in understanding that he is absent today?
Yes. He'd had a trip to Everest planned,
ああ　かねてからの予告どおり　エベレストで避暑中だ
so he's there now, beating the heat.
Good. A confidential strategy is essential for an assassination.
Karuizawa? If you're serious, you'll go to Mt. Everest! To the peak!
ならばよし
作戦の機密保持こそ　暗殺の要だ
I see.
なるほど
First, we destroy the seven promised tentacles,
先に約束の７本の触手を破壊し
then the entire class immediately jumps in to finish him off.
間髪入れずクラス全員で攻撃して　やつを仕留める
So far, so good...
それは分かるが…
But what's this very first step: "psychological warfare"?
この一番最初の精神攻撃というのは何だ
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
First we throw him off, blunting his moves.
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
まず動揺させて　動きを鈍らせるんです
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Psychological Warfare
Strategy Planning Document 1
Secret
Korosensei was scavenging for dirty magazines earlier.
この前さ　殺せんせー　エロ本拾い読みしてたんすよ
Stag
クラスの皆さんには絶対内緒ですよ
Just don't tell your classmates, all right?
Stag
So he paid each of us off with an ice pop.
って　アイス１本配られたけど…
Stag
As if that'd be enough to keep our mouths shut in this day and age!
今どき　アイスで口止めできるわけねえだろ
クラス全員で散々にいびってやるぜ
The entire class will be ganging up and picking on him!
First we'll corner him with that
blackmail material... and more.
他にもゆするネタは幾つか確保してますから
まずはこれを使って追い込みます
A brutal assassination method indeed.
残酷な暗殺法だ…
But the key is that final, killing blow.
しかし　肝心なのはとどめを刺す最後の射撃
Pinpoint timing and accurate aim will be crucial.
正確なタイミングと精密な狙いが不可欠だが…
Are you worried about this class' firepower?
不安か　このクラスの射撃能力は
Quite the opposite. Those two in particular are outstanding.
いいや　逆だ
特にあの２人は素晴らしい
Chiba Ryuunosuke.
千葉龍之介
He excels at spatial calculations.
彼は空間計算にたけている
As a long-distance sniper, he's second to none.
遠距離射撃で　並ぶ者のないスナイパーだ
速水凛香は　手先の正確さと動体視力のバランスが良く
Hayami Rinka has a nice balance of dexterous fingers and kinetic visual acuity.
She's a soldier who's well equipped to take down a moving target.
動く標的を仕留めることに優れたソルジャー
Neither is very assertive.
どちらも主張が強い性格ではなく　結果で語る仕事人タイプ
They're the professional type, so their results do the talking.
俺の教え子に欲しいくらいだ
I would even take them for my own students.
The others are at a respectable level as well.
他の者も良いレベルにまとまっている
Good job identifying and nurturing their talents in such a short time.
短期間でよく見いだし　育てたものだ
I see plenty of potential here.
彼らなら　十分に可能性がある
狙いが安定しただろう
See how your aim has stabilized?
人によっては　立て膝よりあぐらで撃つのが向いている
Some shoot better cross-legged than with one knee up.
Yes, sir!
は…はい
Now that's a pro!
さすが本職
君　呼吸が合わせずらそうだな
You seem to be having trouble keeping pace with others.
無理をせず　自分に合うスタイルで射撃に臨めばいい
Don't force yourself. Instead, go for a firing style that suits you.
一つ聞いてみたくなった
I wanted to ask him something,
this man who knew everything about being an assassin...
殺し屋のことを知り尽くしているこの人に
ロヴロさん
Lovro-san?
この少年…
This boy...
Yes?
何だ
What's the very best assassin like?
一番優れた殺し屋って　どんな人なんですか
On closer inspection, he has what it takes.
よくよく見れば　素質がある
And what's more...
おまけに…
So you're interested in the world of assassins, eh?
興味があるのか　殺し屋の世界に
Oh, uh, th-that's not why I...
いや　そういうわけじゃ
Well, there's only one person on this planet
そうだな…　最高の殺し屋
who can be called the very best assassin.
そう呼べるのはこの地球上にたった一人
この業界にはよくあることだが
As is often the case in this line of work, no one knows his real name.
彼の本名は誰も知らない
They know him by a single alias.
ただ一言のあだ名で呼ばれている
Namely:
いわく
"The Reaper."
死神と
Elusive, incomparably cold-blooded, and with piles of bodies in his wake,
神出鬼没　冷酷無比
おびただしい数のしかばねを積み上げ　死そのものと呼ばれるに至った男
he is known as Death himself.
君たちがこのまま殺しあぐねているのなら
If you keep having trouble killing your target...
the Reaper will show up sooner or later.
いつかは　やつが姿を現すだろう
If someone like that might be coming,
we can't let this island chance pass us by!
そんな人が…
いよいよ南の島のチャンスは逃せない
では　少年よ
Very well, young man.
I shall teach you a deadly technique.
君には必殺技を授けてやろう
Deadly?
必殺…
Yes: a move guaranteed to kill, from this pro assassin to you.
そうだ　プロの殺し屋が直接教える必殺技だ
そして　南の島の暗殺ツアーが幕を開ける
After that, our tropical-island assassination tour began in earnest.
Not a boat... Anything but a boat!
船はヤバい…　船はマジでヤバい…
Everything in my head is going to spill right out!
先生　頭の中身が全部まとめて飛び出そうです
Korosensei's Weak Point #8:
Prone to motion sickness
Oh! Get up, Korosensei, get up! You can see it now!
起きて　起きて　殺せんせー　見えてきたよ
Six hours from Tokyo!
東京から６時間
殺せんせーを殺す場所だぜ
The place where we'll kill Korosensei!
The island!
島だ
Welcome to the Fukuma Resort Hotel!
ようこそ　普久間島リゾートホテルへ
Please enjoy this tropical juice with our compliments.
サービスのトロピカルジュースでございます
Man, this is the life!
いや～　最高
景色全部が鮮やかで明るいな
Everything's just so bright and vibrant!
We can go directly to the beach from the hotel.
ホテルから直行でビーチに行けるんですね
様々なレジャーも用意してあるようです
Looks like they have plenty of leisure activities available, too.
We'll save the you-know-what till after dinner.
例のあれは夕飯の後にやるからさ　まずは遊ぼうぜ　殺せんせー
First, let's have some fun, Korosensei!
修学旅行のときみたく　班別行動でさ
In groups, like we did on our school trip!
I'm all for it. Play hard, kill hard!
賛成です
よく遊び　よく殺す
That's what makes this an assassination vacation!
それでこそ　暗殺教室の夏休みです
Hey, why's that one glider going so fast?
おい　何か一機だけ妙に速いぞ
垂直旋回　左ひねり込みとか　絶対不可能なはずなんだが…
There's no way he should be able to pull off a turn that sharp followed by a barrel roll!
No fair, Korosensei!
ずりーよ　殺せんせー
動力の性能が違い過ぎ
The power difference here is just way too great!
Maximum instantaneous velocity measured at 150 kilometers per hour.
瞬間最大時速１５０ｋｍを計測しました
With a fighter jet, it all comes down to the engine.
戦闘機の性能は　結局のところエンジンの差です
Who's that supposed to be?
そんで　誰だよ　そのコスプレ
堀越二郎です
Horikoshi Jirou.
それ　中身の方
No, that's the guy who voiced him!
分かりづれえよ　ご本人も飛ぶ方じゃなくて作る方
Too hard!
Besides, he didn't fly 'em, he just built 'em!
色々　違和感あり過ぎ
It's just all wrong!
Group 1 is doing a good job of throwing him off.
うまいことやってんな　１班の陽動
やるもんだね
They sure are—and with a little assassination in the mix.
ちゃんと暗殺も交ぜて　他の班に目がいかないようにしてる
They're trying not to draw his attention to the other groups.
Yeah.
We're up next! Let's do what we have to do and get changed ASAP!
次はうちの班に来る番だよ
やることやって　すぐに着替えないと
おお
Got it!
We make it look like we're having fun, but we're dead serious.
遊びに見せ掛けて　僕らは真剣だ
We give the place a good once-over
プランどおり　暗殺ができるかどうか
to see if we can kill him according to plan.
綿密に現地をチェックして回る
何ですか　先生　その模様は
What kind of pattern is that, Korosensei?
A sunburn. Only the frontmost point of the glider was shading me.
日焼けしました
グライダーの先端部分だけ影になってて
さて　君たち４班はイルカを見るそうですね
Now, Group 4 is going dolphin-watching, yes?
Yep! In a boat, though. Is that okay?
はい　船だけど　大丈夫ですか
Sea-rtainly!
オーライシー
一つの班が殺せんせーと遊ぶ間に
While one group hangs out with Korosensei,
他の班も着々と準備を進める
the rest work on their preparations.
Where's Korosensei?
殺せんせーは
Touring deep-sea caves with Group 3.
今　３班と海底洞窟巡りしてる
No way he can see us here.
こっちの様子は絶対に見えないよ
Then we're free to pick out our sniper spots.
じゃあ　今なら　射撃スポット選び放題だな
さくっと決めちゃいますか
Let's make it quick.
Those two sure are cool customers.
渋いな　あの２人
They already feel like total pros.
もはや　仕事人の風格だ
な…何よ　これ
Wh-What the hell?
The beach is utterly deserted!
ビーチから　人っ子一人いなくなったわ
The last guest just left.
さっき帰ったのが最後の客だ
なっ
The E Class has rented out the hotel and its environs.
このホテルと辺り一帯はＥ組が貸し切った
You know that's overkill!
余計なことすんじゃないわよ
何で私の水着デビューはいつもこうなの
Why does this happen every time I step out in a swimsuit?!
This is one large-scale assassination plan—the biggest one yet.
今までにない大規模な暗殺計画　ここまでは完全に予定どおりだ
So far, it's gone off without a hitch.
C'mon, Karasuma. I want to bewitch someone!
ねぇ～　烏間～　悩殺したいの
ねぇ
C'mooon!
The only thing left to worry about...
あと　残る心配は…
H-Hey, wait—
ちょ…　何よ　積極的じゃない
Look at you, taking charge!
We might be alone with each other, but I wasn't expect—
まさか　二人きりだからって　このまま…
What was that for?!
何すんのよ
イリーナ　お前に聞いておきたい
There's something I need to ask you, Irina.
You, the pro assassin, said it yourself:
プロの殺し屋のお前は言ったな
it's not often that your work goes as expected.
仕事は　プランどおりいくことの方が少ないと
Yes, that's right. I saw the documents.
ええ　そうよ
計画書見たけど
こんだけ複雑な計画だったら　一つや二つはどこかずれるわ
Chances are a complex plan like this will go off the rails once or twice.
Do I look like I'm just having fun here?
この私が遊んでるだけに見える
I'm gunning for my share of the spoils, of course.
真剣におこぼれを狙ってるのよ
がきどもの計画がずれたとき　その結果　私にチャンスが回ってきたら
I'll get my opportunity when the brats' plan goes awry—
決して　逃さないようにね
and I won't let it get away.
無事に暗殺が終わればいいが…
I just hope the assassination goes smoothly.
Phew! What fun that was!
いや～　遊んだ　遊んだ
No wonder I'm so tanned!
おかげで　真っ黒に焼けました
黒過ぎだろ
That's beyond tanned!
Even your teeth are tanned.
歯まで黒く焼けやがって
もう表情が読み取れないよ
So much for picking up on your expressions.
All right, Korosensei, after dinner comes the assassination.
じゃあ　殺せんせー　飯の後で暗殺なんで
Yes, yes. First, the shipboard restaurant!
は～い　まずは船上レストランに行きましょう
Hasn't that octopus had enough fun for one day?
どんだけ満喫してんだ　あのタコ
こちとら　楽しむふりして準備すんの大変だったのによ
Meanwhile, we got to pretend to have fun while we got everythin' ready!
Well, if we kill him today, we can just enjoy ourselves tomorrow.
まっ　今日殺せりゃ　あしたは何も考えずに楽しめるじゃん
I guess. Let's put in some effort and finish the job!
まあな　今回ぐらい気合入れてやるとすっか
Here we are,
夕食はこの貸し切り船上レストランで
at the shipboard restaurant we've rented out.
夜の海を堪能しながら　ゆっくり食べましょう
Let's slowly savor our meal as we take in the night sea.
なるほど
I get it.
まずは　たっぷりと船に酔わせて　戦力をそごうというわけですか
First you'll get me good and seasick to weaken my capabilities, eh?
Of course. That's Assassination 101.
当然です　これも暗殺の基本の一つですから
実に正しい
You're so right.
ですが　そううまくいくでしょうか
But will it really work that well?
Seasickness is no match for a teacher who's all pumped up anticipating an assassination—
暗殺を前に気合の乗った先生にとって　船酔いなど恐るるに…
だから　黒いよ
You're too dark!
Am I really that dark?
そんなに黒いですか
Forget your expression, we can't even tell front from back!
表情どころか　前も後ろも分かんないわ
It's too confusing. Do something about it, would you?
ややこしいから　何とかしてよ
お忘れですか　皆さん
Have you forgotten, students?
I can molt—and in so doing, shed this dark skin!
先生には　脱皮があることを
黒い皮を脱ぎ捨てれば
There! Back to normal.
ほら　元通り
That's your once-a-month molt!
月１回の脱皮だ
Just another of its uses.
こんな使い方もあるんですよ
I tend to save it for particularly sticky situations, but...
本来はヤバいときの奥の手ですが…
バッカでー…　暗殺前に自分で戦力減らしてやんの
What an idiot, hobbling himself before an assassination!
That's right: just once a month.
どうしていまだに　こんなドジ　殺せないんだろ
How have we not been able to kill this screw-up yet?
I guess at least you can see my expressions now.
We'd spent all summer doing special training in preparation for this day.
この日のために　夏休みに入ってひそかに特訓してきた
仕込みも万全
Everything was in place.
今度こそ　殺せんせーに　このやいばを届かせるんだ
This time... This time, our blades would reach him.
All right, Korosensei. Dinner's over.
さーて　殺せんせー　飯の後はいよいよだ
会場はこちらですぜ
Here's where we're meeting.
A floating chapel, away from the hotel.
このホテルの離れにある水上チャペル
Take a seat, Korosensei.
さあ　席に着けよ　殺せんせー
ここなら　逃げ場はありません
There's nowhere for you to run here.
It'll be a fun assassination.
楽しい暗殺
まずは　映画鑑賞から始めようぜ
We'll start with a movie.
君たちの知恵と工夫と本気の努力
Your intelligence, your inventiveness, and your earnest efforts...
Those are what I most look forward to.
それを見るのが先生の何よりの楽しみです
全力の暗殺を期待しています
I expect a no-holds-barred assassination!
太陽が射す　閉ざした瞼の裏側に赤い残像
The sun shines
taiyou ga sasu
On the back of my closed eyelids
tozashita mabuta no uragawa ni
I see red afterimages
akai zanzou
革の鞄に　ノートとペンを　さあ歩き出そう
With a notebook and a pen in my leather bag
kawa no kaban ni nooto to pen wo
I go for a walk
saa arukidasou
描いても描いても　綺麗にならない
I keep drawing, but I can't get it to look pretty
kaitemo kaitemo kirei ni naranai
選んだ絵の具に　罪はない
My choice of colors is not to blame
eranda enogu ni tsumi wa nai
昨日の夜中に見た流れ星　まだ覚えている
I still remember the shooting star I saw last night
kinou no yonaka ni mita nagareboshi mada oboeteiru
I was waiting for…
I was waiting for...
Hello shooting-star Hello shooting-star again
Hello, shooting star
Hello, shooting star, again
待っていたよ
I was waiting
matteita yo
夢を見るあの子はずっと
The girl of many dreams
yume wo miru ano ko wa zutto
ここにいるの　Ah　Ah
Is always here
koko ni iru no
あの日のまま　Ah　Ah
Just like you did that day
ano hi no mama
また光って
Shine again
mata hikatte
外国産のカブトムシやクワガタは９９年に輸入が解禁されて以来
国内で多く流通するようになりました
これらが野外に放たれると在来種が絶滅することがあります
実際２００３年に北海道で
アトラスオオカブトムシが見つかっていますよ　倉橋さん
次回　暗殺教室　決行の時間